Guide to the Leo K. Bustad Papers 1912-2005
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- Series 2: Professional Papers
  - Subseries 2.7: Publications
    - Get 'Em While They're Young, 1985-1986 (Folder 25, Item 467)
    - Grief is the Price of Loving, 1984 December (Folder 25, Item 468)
    - Guinea-Pig Hogs, undated (Folder 25, Item 469)
    - Health Benefits of Human-Animal Interaction, 1993 (Folder 25, Item 470)
    - Health Benefits of Pets: Historical Perspective, 1988 (Folder 25, Item 471)
    - Hearing Dogs: An Experiment in Training, undated (Folder 25, Item 472)
    - Hematopoietic Changes in Beagles Fed 90(SR), 1969 (Folder 25, Item 473)
    - Historical Perspectives on the Human-Animal Bond, 1984 (Folder 25, Item 474)
    - Historical Perspectives on Human-Animal Interactions, undated (Folder 25, Item 475)
    - Historical Perspectives on the Role of Pets in Therapeutic Programs, undated (Folder 25, Item 476)
    - History of Veterinary Curriculum, 1986 (Folder 25, Item 477)
    - Housing and Handling of Minature Swine, 1967 (Folder 25, Item 478)
    - How Animal Make People Human and Humane, 1979 September (Folder 25, Item 479)
    - Human Animal Bond and One Medicine, 1984 (Folder 25, Item 480)
    - The Human Animal Bond: An Overview, 1984 (Folder 25, Item 481)
    - The Human-Animal Bond in the Public Health Curriculum, 1983 December (Folder 25, Item 482)
    - The Human-Animal Bond: Our Profession's Responsibilities, undated (Folder 25, Item 483)
    - The Human Companion Animal Bond and the Veterinarian, 1981 November (Folder 25, Item 484)
    - The Impact of Food Animal Research on Regulatory Medicine, undated (Folder 25, Item 485)
    - Impact of History, Literature and Art on Teaching Reverence for Life, 1983 Spring (Folder 25, Item 486)
    - Impact of People on Laboratory Animals: Decisions and Diseases, undated (Folder 25, Item 487)
    - Impact of People on Other Animals: Disease and Duty, undated (Folder 25, Item 488)
    - The Importance of Animals to the Well Being of People, 1985 December (Folder 25, Item 489)
    - Inferences on Radiation Carcinogenesis Revealed by Selected Studies in Animals, 1976 (Folder 25, Item 490)
    - The Interrelationships of Movement and Language in Animal Facilitated Therapy Settings, undated (Folder 25, Item 491)
    - Investigators' Interrelationship with Laboratory Animals, 1987 January (Folder 25, Item 492)
    - I (131) Milk and Thyroid of Dairy Cattle Following a Single Contamination Event and Prolonged Daily Administration, undated (Folder 25, Item 493)
    - Laboratory Scientists and Their Role in Human/Animal Bonding, 1983 (Folder 25, Item 494)
    - The Living Bond: An Afterword by LKB, undated (Folder 25, Item 495)
    - Living Together: People, Animals, Environment - A Personal Historical Perspective, 1988 (Folder 25, Item 496)
    - Man and Beast Interface: An Overview of Our Interrelationships, undated (Folder 25, Item 497)
    - Metabolism of 131 (I) in Sheep and Swine, 1962 (Folder 25, Item 498)
    - Minature Swine: Development, Management and Ultilization, 1968 (Folder 25, Item 499)
    - A Nationwide Study of Veterinary Students' Values and Attitudes on Ethical Issues, undated (Folder 25, Item 500)
    - The Northwest Regional Program in Veterinary Medical Education: An Overview, 1977 (Folder 25, Item 501)
    - Nurtured Children: An Endangered Species?, 1994 (Folder 25, Item 502)
    - Optimal Placement of Pet with Institutionalized Elderly: A Systems Approach, 1981 February (Folder 25, Item 503)
    - Our Profession's Responsibilities Regarding the Living Bond: People, Animals, Environment, 1988 March (Folder 25, Item 504)
    - Our Professional Responsibilities Relative to Human-Animal Interactions, 1984 July (Folder 25, Item 505)
    - Our Responsibilities to the Natural World, undated (Folder 25, Item 506)
    - People-Animal Interaction: A Look Back - A Look Ahead, 1989 (Folder 25, Item 507)
    - Pet-Assisted Therapy - An Idea That's Catching On, 1993 (Folder 25, Item 508)
    - Pet Education Partnership, 1989 (Folder 25, Item 509)
    - Pets-For-People Therapy, 1976 (Folder 25, Item 510)
    - Physiology, undated (Folder 25, Item 511)
    - Pigs: From BC -2000 AD: From Outhouse to Penthouse, 1986 (Folder 25, Item 512)
    - Pigs in the Laboratory, 1966 (Folder 25, Item 513)
    - Placement of Animal with the Elderly: Benefits and Strategies, 1982 (Folder 25, Item 514)
    - Preface - Small Animal Practice, 1985 March (Folder 25, Item 515)
    - Preliminary Observations on Metabolism and Toxicity of Plutonium in Miniature Swine, 1962 (Folder 25, Item 516)
    - Preliminary Observations on Using a Synthetic Milk for Raising Pigs from Birth, 1948 (Folder 25, Item 517)
    - The Problem and Paradox That is Cancer, undated (Folder 25, Item 518)
    - Radiation and Aging, undated (Folder 25, Item 519)
    - Recent Discoveries About Our Relationships with the Natural World, 1990 (Folder 25, Item 520)
    - Reflections on the Human-Animal Bond, 1996 (Folder 25, Item 521)
    - Relief and Prevention of Grief, 1984 (Folder 25, Item 522)
    - Schwein und Mensch sind Bruder (Pig and Man are Brother), undated (Folder 25, Item 523)
    - Radioisotopes and Environmental Circumstances: Significance from Nuclear Industry Effluents in Animal Populations, undated (Folder 25, Item 524)
    - The Significance of Radionuclide Contamination in Ruminants, 1965 (Folder 25, Item 525)
    - The Significance of the Human-Animal Bond for Animal Control Personnel, undated (Folder 25, Item 526)
    - Somatic Effects of Radiation: Tumorigenesis and Aging, undated (Folder 25, Item 527)
    - Special Edition, 1987 May (Folder 25, Item 528)
    - Thyroid Function in Domestic Animals, 1970 (Folder 25, Item 529)
    - Toxicity of Radioiodine, 1953 (Folder 25, Item 530)
    - Toxicity of I (131) in Sheep, undated (Folder 25, Item 531)
    - The Use of Miniature Swine in Gerontological Research, 1968 (Folder 25, Item 532)
    - The Use of Pets in Therapy, 1978 October (Folder 25, Item 533)
    - Use of Pigs in Biomedical Research, 1965 (Folder 25, Item 534)
    - The Veterinarian's Role in Atomic Bomb Fall-out, 1954 (Folder 25, Item 535)
    - Vets Have Responsibilities in Animal-Facilitated Therapy, 1981 (Folder 25, Item 536)
    - WSU's Peripatetic Dean, 1978-1979 (Folder 25, Item 537)
  - Subseries 2.8: Day Planners
    - 1974 - 2 planners (Folder 26)
    - 1975 - 2 planners (Folder 26)
    - 1976 - 2 planners (Folder 26)
    - 1977 - 1 planner (Folder 26)
    - 1978 - 1 planner (Folder 26)
    - 1979 - 2 planners (Folder 26)
    - 1980 - 2 planners (Folder 26)
    - 1981 - 2 planners (Folder 26)
    - 1982 - 2 planners (Folder 26)
    - 1983 - 1 planner (Folder 26)
    - 1984 - 1 planner (Folder 26)
    - 1985 - 1 planner (Folder 26)
    - 1988 - 2 planners (Folder 26)
  - Subseries 2.9: Ephemera
    - National Academies of Practice Distinguished Practitioner medal, undated (Folder 27)
    - University of Georgia Bicentennial medal, 1985 (Folder 27)
    - Pigs in the Laboratory oversized photograph, 1966 (Folder 27)
    - Reprint of "Clinic: Number One of a Series from Shell's Pictorial Treasury of Veterinary Medicine", undated (Folder 27)
    - Reprint of "The Cow Doctor: Number Two of a Series from Shell's Pictorial Treasury of Veterinary Medicine", undated (Folder 27)
    - American College of Veterinary Surgeons certificate: "Distinguished Guest and Presenter of the Mark W. Allen Lecture", 1986 February 27 (Folder 27)
    - Brass plaque of Veterinarian's Oath adopted by the American Veterinary Medicine Association, 1954 August (Folder 27)
- Series 3: Correspondence
  This series observes Dr. Bustad’s arrangement of correspondence by general alphabetical order and specifically by person and includes correspondence with Sophie Engelhard Craighead, Dean Borje Gustafsson, and Sister Pauline Quinn.
  - Subseries 3.1: General Correspondence
    - "C" (1 of 2), 1976-1977 (Folder 28, Item 538)
    - "C" (2 of 2), 1976-1977 (Folder 28, Item 539)
    - "D" (1 of 2), 1976-1977 (Folder 28, Item 540)
    - "D" (2 of 2), 1976-1977 (Folder 28, Item 541)
    - "E" (1 of 2), 1975-1977 (Folder 28, Item 542)
    - "E" (2 of 2), 1975-1977 (Folder 28, Item 543)
    - "F", 1976-1977 (Folder 28, Item 544)
    - "G", 1974-1977 (Folder 29, Item 545)
    - "H" (1 of 2), 1976-1977 (Folder 29, Item 546)
    - "H" (2 of 2), 1976-1977 (Folder 29, Item 547)
    - "I-J", 1976-1977 (Folder 29, Item 548)
    - "K", 1975-1977 (Folder 29, Item 549)
    - "L", 1976-1977 (Folder 30, Item 550)
    - "M" (1 of 3), 1975-1977 (Folder 30, Item 551)
    - "M" (2 of 3), 1975-1977 (Folder 30, Item 552)
    - "M" (3 of 3), 1975-1977 (Folder 30, Item 553)
    - "N", 1976-1977 (Folder 30, Item 554)
    - "O", 1976-1977 (Folder 30, Item 555)
    - "P", 1976-1977 (Folder 30, Item 556)
    - "R", 1976-1977 (Folder 31, Item 557)
    - "S" (1 of 2), 1976-1977 (Folder 31, Item 558)
    - "S" (2 of 2), 1976-1977 (Folder 31, Item 559)
    - "T", 1976-1977 (Folder 31, Item 560)
    - "U-V", 1976-1977 (Folder 31, Item 561)
    - "W-Z" (1 of 2), 1974-1977 (Folder 31, Item 562)
    - "W-Z" (2 of 2), 1974-1977 (Folder 31, Item 563)
  - Subseries 3.2: Correspondence by Person
    - Antoinette de Monaco, Princesse, 1989-1990 (Folder 32, Item 564)
    - Bill Balaban, 1982-1990 (Folder 32, Item 565)
    - James Brady, 1986 (Folder 32, Item 566)
    - Barbara Bush, 1988 (Folder 32, Item 567)
    - Samuel A. Corson, 1979-1998 (Folder 32, Item 568)
    - Sophie Engelhard Craighead, 1982-1999 (Folder 32, Item 569)
    - Richard Dege/Bethel, 1980 (Folder 32, Item 570)
    - The Delta Society, 1981-1994 (Folder 32, Item 571)
    - Florence Dunbar, 1988-1990 (Folder 32, Item 572)
    - Ian Dunbar, 1987 (Folder 32, Item 573)
    - Toni and Ed, 1992-1995 (Folder 32, Item 574)
    - John Eccles, 1981 (Folder 32, Item 575)
    - I. Eibl-Eibesfeldt, 1983 (Folder 32, Item 576)
    - Gil Glass, 1987-1996 (Folder 32, Item 577)
    - Betsy Greene, 1993-1994 (Folder 32, Item 578)
    - Clover Gowing, 1990-1994 (Folder 32, Item 579)
    - Dean Borje Gustafsson, 1990-2001 (Folder 32, Item 580)
    - Maurice and Kathleen Hitchcock, 1983-1984 (Folder 32, Item 581)
    - Mike Malcom, 1983, 1990 (Folder 32, Item 582)
    - Dr. Bernard J. Pinckney, 1976-2003 (Folder 32, Item 583)
    - Pauline Quinn (1 of 2), 1979-1997 (Folder 32, Item 584)
    - Pauline Quinn (2 of 2), 1979-1997 (Folder 33, Item 585)
    - Dr. Sam B. Ross, Jr., circa 1980s (Folder 33, Item 586)
    - Paul Tournier, 1972-1986 (Folder 33, Item 587)
    - E.O. Wilson, 1988-1989 (Folder 33, Item 588)
    - Bruce A. Zirpel, 1996-1998 (Folder 33, Item 589)
- Series 4: Personal Papers
  This series includes photographs, certificates and honors, newspaper clippings, Christmas letters, curriculum vitae, memorial service notes, paperwork related to Dr. Bustad’s retirement from the United States Army, and other personal materials. This series contains restricted materials.
  - Photographs - personal, 1930s-1990s (Folder 34, Item 590)
  - Photographs and drawings, circa 1940s-circa 1970s (Folder 34, Item 591)
  - Photographs - personal, circa 1960s (Folder 34, Item 592)
  - Photographs - personal, 1950s-1990s (Folder 34, Item 593)
  - Leo K. Bustad's World War II timeline, circa 1944-1945 (Folder 34, Item 594)
  - Early career, 1945-1973 (Folder 34, Item 595)
  - "Talks" (1 of 2), 1957-1965 (Folder 34, Item 596)
  - "Talks" (2 of 2), 1957-1965 (Folder 34, Item 597)
  - Slides - personal, 1957-1994 (Folder 34, Item 598)
  - Certificates/honors, 1957-1994 (Folder 34, Item 599)
  - "Bustad-personal" (1 of 2), 1962-1995 (Folder 34, Item 600)
  - "Bustad-personal" (2 of 2), 1962-1995 (Folder 35, Item 601)
  - Newspaper clippings and honors (1 of 2), 1965-1997 (Folder 35, Item 602)
  - Newspaper clippings and honors (2 of 2), 1965-1997 (Folder 35, Item 603)
  - Holden Village, 1969-1997 (Folder 35, Item 604)
  - "To check and file", circa 1960s-1997 (Folder 35, Item 605)
  - Appointment to deanship at Washington State University, 1973 (Folder 35, Item 606)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1996 (Folder 35, Item 607)
  - National Academy of Sciences "An Affirmation of Inquiry and Expression", 1976 (Folder 35, Item 608)
  - "Bustad-media", 1976-1994 (Folder 35, Item 609)
  - Christmas letters, 1977-1996 (Folder 35, Item 610)
  - The Peripatetic Dean, 1978-1981 (Folder 35, Item 611)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1980-1996 (Folder 35, Item 612)
  - Memorandum of development, 1981 November 30 (Folder 35, Item 613)
  - Bulloch sheep case, 1982-1983 (Folder 35, Item 614)
  - College of Veterinary Medicine honor roll, 1983 (Folder 36, Item 615)
  - "Merry Christmas from the Class of 1984" (Folder 36, Item 616)
  - Itineraries/speaking schedules, 1983-1989 (Folder 36, Item 617)
  - Leo K. Bustad Endowment Fund, 1985 (Folder 36, Item 618)
  - Karen Bustad "Dancing in Africa", 1985 (Folder 36, Item 619)
  - Fifty year reunion Lincoln High School and Stanwood Union High School class of 1937, 1987 August 08 (Folder 36, Item 620)
  - Lifeforce flyer, 1987 (Folder 36, Item 621)
  - Cartoons, circa 1990s (Folder 36, Item 622)
  - "Hard copy of book Compassion: Our Last Great Hope", 1990 (Folder 36, Item 623)
  - World Small Animal Veterinary Association award, 1990-1991 (Folder 36, Item 624)
  - "Bustad-trees", 1990-1999 (Folder 36, Item 625)
  - Birdwatching, 1992-1994 (Folder 36, Item 626)
  - Church bulletin - flowers in memory of dog Bridget, 1994 February 27 (Folder 36, Item 627)
  - "49 reunion", 1949, 1994 (Folder 36, Item 628)
  - Leo K. Bustad's notes for own memorial, circa 1998 (Folder 36, Item 629)
  - Memorial service programs, 1998 (Folder 36, Item 630)
  - Signe and Leo Bustad obituaries, 1998 (Folder 36, Item 631)
  - "Bustad memorial thank yous", 1998-1999 (Folder 36, Item 632)
  - Remembrances following Dr. Bustad's death, 1998-1999 (Folder 36, Item 633)
  - "Bustad-tree", 1999 (Folder 36, Item 634)
  - National Science Foundation National Endowment for the Humanities Ethics curriculum proposal, undated (Folder 36, Item 635)
  - National Science Foundation National Endowment for the Humanities Ethics curriculum proposal RESTRICTED, undated (Folder 36, Item 636)
  - "Norwegians", undated (Folder 36, Item 637)
  - Transparencies, undated (Folder 36, Item 638)
  - Removal from active status in the United States Army Reserve, 1973 November (Folder 37, Item 639)
  - Removal from active status in the United States Army Reserve RESTRICTED, 1973 November (Folder 37, Item 640)
  - Certificate of retirement United States Army, 1980 January (Folder 37, Item 641)
  - Certificate of retirement United States Army RESTRICTED, 1980 January (Folder 37, Item 642)
  - Leo K. Bustad's personal health diary RESTRICTED until 2073, 1990-1994 (Folder 37, Item 643)
- Series 5: Audiovisual Materials
  This series contains multiple formats related to Dr. Bustad’s professional and personal interests, including the human-animal bond, animal behavior, animal-assisted therapy, veterinary medicine and research, and ethics and values. Materials are by Dr. Bustad as well as by others.
  - Subseries 5.1: Reel to Reel
    - "Ag. USA" (4x4.25" box), undated (Folder 38)
    - Edward R. Murrow, 1962 June 03 (Folder 38)
    - Holden Village talks, 1969 (Folder 38)
  - Subseries 5.2: U-matics
    - Komo News: "Handicapped children/equine no audio", undated (Folder 38)
    - NIC Forum #430 Jack Alexander "Small Animal Tx" 12 minutes, 1981 April 20 (Folder 38)
    - "The Right to Choose" England 30 minutes, undated (Folder 38)
    - Excerpts: 1. Human-companion animal bond 2. 60 Minutes (monkeys) 3. Handi-dogs 4. Canine companion, undated (Folder 38)
    - Planned pethood AUMA film 10 minutes, undated (Folder 38)
    - People-Pet Partnership: Canine companion for independence, undated (Folder 38)
    - Intro to PPP LKB, Linda Hines, Barbara Morgan, RN, 1983 April 11 (Folder 38)
    - Companion animal bond, Latham tape 30 minutes, 1982 October 26 (Folder 38)
    - Pet-facillitated therapy Lima OH program, undated (Folder 38)
    - Paws for help, undated (Folder 38)
    - Palouse 4th grade: Dogs as pets presentation Dr. Schultz, T. Ryan, undated (Folder 38)
    - People-Pet Partnership (King TV), undated (Folder 38)
    - People-Pet Partnership, undated (Folder 38)
    - That's Incredible #53 horse wobblers segment part 1 of 1, 1982 March 16 (Folder 38)
    - Wade Simpson interview Q-6 TV on Dean Bustad and Vet School, ?1981 (Folder 39)
    - College of Veterinary Medicine children's program, undated (Folder 39)
    - People-Pet Partnership: public school program, ?1983 (Folder 39)
    - King TV (PPP), undated (Folder 39)
    - "An Institution Without Walls" L.K. Bustad, undated (Folder 39)
    - Gross anatomy lab tape: Wade Simpson interviewing Dr. Buckstein about course, undated (Folder 39)
    - PPP King TV, undated (Folder 39)
    - "Who Cares Anyway" Toronto Humane Society 30 minutes, undated (Folder 39)
    - Behavior: canine: part I of III (adult temp. test) Ryan, undated (Folder 39)
    - Behavior: canine: part II of III, Ryan, 1982 October (Folder 39)
    - Behavior: canine: part III of III Ryan, undated (Folder 39)
    - Equine therapy, KOMO radio/television 3:08 minutes, 1981 April 24 (Folder 39)
    - "Household Pets" Dr. Robert Ergan, 1980 April 09 (Folder 39)
    - Ability, not disability, undated (Folder 39)
    - "It's Ability, Not Disability" 30 minutes (Latham Withit Series), undated (Folder 39)
    - Gayle Turco, RN Lathah Care Center, Becky Scott, Coordinator, Terry Ryan, undated (Folder 40)
    - NIC #429 public-forum WSU College of Veterinary Medicine "Orig. training tapes. Once damaged - check before suing. KP", undated (Folder 40)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 40)
    - PETE Beginning I non-edited, undated (Folder 40)
    - PETE - master (slides to music) Barb Brock, 1987 (Folder 40)
    - My experience at Auschwitz Mrs. Mira Kimmelman 49 minutes, 1986 April (Folder 40)
  - Subseries 5.3: VHS cassettes
    - Companion animals and mental health: defining common ground between veterinary medicine and psychiatry Dr. M. J. McCullock, MD presented at WSU, 1972 (Folder 40)
    - Canine behavior - Terry Ryan Vol. I of III, Continuing University Studies WSU, 1982 October (Folder 40)
    - Canine behavior - Terry Ryan Vol. II of III, Continuing University Studies WSU, 1982 October (Folder 40)
    - Canine behavior - Terry Ryan Vol. III of III, Continuing University Studies WSU, 1982 October (Folder 40)
    - Companion Animal Association of Arizona Conference (digitized at MASC MS2008_196_01 LB 031985), 1985 March 21-22 (Folder 40)
    - Leo K. Bustad luncheon/dedication of the Leo K. Bustad Veterinary Science Building, 1985 April 05 (Folder 40)
    - Handicapped vaulting demonstration IIAVA National Festival Cal Poly Pomona, 1985 August (Folder 40)
    - Partnership in equine therapy and education slides to music B. Brock, 1987 (Folder 40)
    - Companion animals, 1988 (Folder 40)
    - Rider evaluations, 1989 Fall (Folder 40)
    - "Water-conserving landscapes: Beautiful, responsible, inviting" 12:23 by L.H. Bummer and V.I. Lohr, 1989 (Folder 40)
    - PETE rider evaluations, 1990 March 29 (Folder 40)
    - PETE training sessions, 1990 Spring (Folder 40)
    - PETE Halloween, 1990 November 01 (Folder 40)
    - PETE riding class practicum, 1991 January 24 (Folder 40)
    - PETE accreditation "Debbie first class good", 1991 April 23 (Folder 40)
    - Niki Singer, Inc Bustad Award Luncheon "dub of edit" 39 minutes, 1991 May 01 (Folder 40)
    - Rider evaluations, 1991 Spring (Folder 40)
    - Animal assisted therapy - a 4-H program featured in a Channel 5 segment of "Evening", 1991 July (Folder 40)
    - PETE Halloween, 1991 (Folder 40)
    - Training session, 1991 (Folder 40)
    - "Pet Pourri" K-1st grade, 1991 (Folder 40)
    - L. Bustad's welcome at Companion Animal Veterinarian of the Year Award, 1992 May 05 (Folder 40)
    - Three minute tribute to Dr. Small by Dr. Leo Bustad, 1992 September (Folder 40)
    - James Rachels, University of Alabama, Birmingham "Darwinism and Ethics", 1992 November 12 (Folder 40)
    - "H.A.B.I.T. - An Amazing Catalyst for Progress" (15:33 minutes) University of Tennessee College of Veterinary Medicine #5 "not for broadcast, duplication prohibited, use restrictions apply", 1992 (Folder 40)
    - Dr. Leo Bustad speaking to A.S. 180 (freshman) students Clark Hall room 149, introduced by Dr. Everett L. Martin, 1995 December 04 (Folder 41)
    - 1995 Delta Society Service and Therapy Animal Awards 18:01 minutes (Folder 41)
    - Roger Williams seminar Marcus Borg, 1996 (Folder 41)
    - "In Celebration of Leo Bustad's Life" Trinity Lutheran Church Pullman, WA, 1998 September 22 (Folder 41)
    - WSU School of Veterinary Medicine class of 1949 "The way we were", undated (Folder 41)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 41)
    - 60 Minutes, Today Show, 3-2-1 Contact, undated (Folder 41)
    - Copy #2, undated (Folder 41)
    - My experience at Auschwitz, undated (Folder 41)
    - Pinellas pet education partnership Eckerd Drug Corp. recruiting tape 3 minutes, undated (Folder 41)
    - Top dog short, undated (Folder 41)
    - Healthy Pets/Healthy People series (duplicate), undated (Folder 41)
    - All About Pets with Dr. Marty Marx demo 7:08, undated (Folder 41)
    - Copy of accreditation tape, undated (Folder 41)
    - Film: "Why Man Creates", undated (Folder 41)
    - How'd They Do That? 6-30, undated (Folder 41)
    - The Latham Foundation presents "Breaking the Cycles of Violence" 26 minutes, undated (Folder 41)
    - PPP, "Intimate Companions", Pullman, WA (digitized at MASC MS2008_19601_PPP), undated (Folder 41)
    - Bustad - PPP - WSU "Jake's Journey" first of the Affection Connection series (1 1/2 hours) taped off satellite, undated (Folder 41)
    - Best Friends by the American Kennel Club, undated (Folder 41)
    - Top Dog "Friends", undated (Folder 41)
    - Dr. Leo Bustad - presentation for AAHABV, duplicate (digitized at MASC MS2008_19603_LB_AAHABV), undated (Folder 41)
    - PETE training session, undated (Folder 41)
    - PPEP 1st and 2nd grades pet professor training 12 minutes Pinellas Animal Foundation promotion - 20 minutes, undated (Folder 41)
    - Latham Foundation's canine companions for independence, undated (Folder 41)
    - PEEGE, undated (Folder 41)
    - "Therapeutic Driving" with Jerry Garner, undated (Folder 41)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 41)
    - Delta Society Renton, WA Sophie Engelhard Craighead Center dedication ceremony 54:15 minutes, undated (Folder 41)
    - The PAL Program - Lorton, VA time 28:45, undated (Folder 41)
  - Subseries 5.4: Audiocassettes
    - Robert Ardrey, 1972 November 17 (Folder 42)
    - Vocations L. Bustad Anchorage, AK, 1977 October (Folder 42)
    - LKB "Who's afraid of pheromones?" one side only, 1980 April 04 (Folder 42)
    - 2nd copy of original mystery sermon to Presbyterian Church, 1983 July 24 (Folder 42)
    - ? VORTAQ: Leo Bustad, undated (Folder 42)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 42)
    - Dr. Leo Bustad Winners Circle Side B George Barber, 1983 December 13 (Folder 42)
    - Wildlife diseases, undated (Folder 42)
    - Harold Knapp, 1979 October 26 (Folder 42)
    - Faculty meeting, ?1990 (Folder 42)
    - Bustad, Leo "how to throw a party" vesper 24 minutes, 1975 August 21 (Folder 42)
    - Letter to Gretchen - L. Bustad Holden, 1975 (Folder 42)
    - A. Rantanem B. Hightower, undated (Folder 42)
    - "One side used for Fred Mauer talk", undated (Folder 42)
    - Brosen, Jan "Anorexia Neurosa and Bolima" 55 minutes, undated (Folder 42)
    - Pacific Health Plan meeting, 1980 June 26 (Folder 42)
    - Careers in veterinary medicine, undated (Folder 42)
    - Guinea pigs copy 15 minutes, undated (Folder 42)
    - Monday Talks both sides, undated (Folder 42)